nwbanktowin.com 2017-12-29

# Website Privacy And Cookies Policy for Nationwide.com

At Nationwide, protecting your privacy is important. We know you are interested in how we collect, use, share, and protect your information. We treat your personal information responsibly and provide you with choices about how we use and share it. This privacy policy describes the choices available to you regarding your personal information and how you can update this information provided on Nationwide’s websites, including nationwide.com, alliedinsurance.com, titan.com, titaninsurancesales.com, and nationwideadvantagemortgage.com (“Nationwide.”)

## Information Collection

We collect information from you automatically through your use of our website, with cookies and similar technology, and when you provide information directly to us through our website. We have described these information collection practices in more detail below.

### Information We Collect Automatically

We gather certain information automatically using cookies along with online technologies, such as beacons, tags, and JavaScript whenever you use our website or mobile app, send us an email, or interact with our emails and advertisements. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser information, internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, session ID, date and time stamp, geolocation, and click stream data. We use this information to:

  * Conduct website and mobile app analysis
  * Recognize your browser or device
  * Remember your preferences and interactions
  * Collect information about our website usage and email responses
  * Log activity on our website
  * Market products or services to you

### Information We Collect Through Cookies and Similar Technology

Nationwide uses third party cookies, beacons, tags, and JavaScript to collect anonymous information and technical data, like your internet protocol (IP) address, operating system, and session ID. Nationwide shares this information with our business partners to manage our online advertising and to recognize visitors’ computers and devices. This allows us to render relevant Nationwide ads to you. This is referred to as behaviorally targeted or interest based ads. Our third party partners also use such technologies for website analysis and to manage the effectiveness of our ads placed on other websites. We do not store your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any sensitive personal information in these cookies and similar technologies. The companies that distribute our ads are only permitted to use or share your information for marketing Nationwide products and services.

Nationwide will share personal information with third parties only in ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. Each of the third parties that we use for our online marketing and tracking efforts should post a privacy policy that fully describes the advertising and data collection activities on their website. However, we cannot guarantee that all of these websites disclose this information.

We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Our business partners who provide certain features on our website or display advertising based upon your web browsing activity may also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. 

### Opting out of behaviorally targeted advertising

If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note that you may continue to see generic or non-targeted ads from these companies after you opt-out.

### How to control cookies

All major internet browsers allow you to block or delete cookies through the privacy features in your browser. Please note that if you block cookies then you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

### Do Not Track

Please note that our system may not recognize Do Not Track headers or requests from some browsers.

### Web Links and Widgets

Other companies or organizations may have links to their websites on our web pages. Our website may also include social media widgets, such as the “share this” buttons and links to third party websites, like Facebook and Twitter. These features may collect your IP address, the page where you visited on our site, and may place a cookie to enable these features to function properly. We are not responsible for how these third parties collect, use, disclose or secure the information that you provide to them. Please read their privacy policies so you can learn how their website uses your information.

### Information We Collect Directly Through Our Website

We collect your personal information on our website when you:

  * Ask a question
  * Use tools and calculators
  * Apply for products or services
  * Complete a form
  * Conduct transactions
  * Apply for a job
  * Send email to us
  * Subscribe to receive email from us
  * Complete website surveys

Personal information is any information that identifies you and describes your relationship with us. Some examples of the personal information that Nationwide may collect include:

  * Name, address, date of birth, and Social Security number
  * Assets and income
  * Property address and value
  * Account and policy information
  * Driver's license number
  * Financial information
  * Credit reports and other consumer report information
  * Information from applications and transactions
  * Any information you provide us
  * Public information

We may collect personal information about you, another insured on your policy, or a beneficiary when applying for a policy or service. We will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided.

If you apply for a product or service, we may collect information from your consumer reports, such as your credit report or motor vehicle report. We may use an "insurance score." An insurance score uses information from your credit report to help predict your future claims. Typical items that could affect an insurance score include payment history, number of revolving, new and collection accounts, bankruptcies, and foreclosures.

You may request the credit report source. Each Nationwide company has different contact information and instructions for requesting this information, so you will want to review the specific privacy policy for the Nationwide product you own. We have included links to these products and companies in the box labeled "Privacy Statement for Your Specific Product."

In rare instances, we may also need to collect your medical information from a medical provider. However, we will not use or share your medical information for marketing, unless you give us your permission.

We retain your personal information while your account is active or as needed to provide you services, such as quoting, re-quoting, and account management. We also retain and use your information as required or permitted by law to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Use of Third Party Data

We may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data. We may combine this data with information we already have about you, which allows us to update our records. Examples of the types of personal information that we may obtain from public sources or third parties may include change of address information from third parties for address standardization and correction. 

### Information We Collect Directly through our SmartRide Program

SmartRide is a usage based insurance program that provides you with personalized feedback to help you make safe driving decisions while allowing you to earn discounts on your insurance premium. If you participate in the SmartRide program, we will gather information using a telematic device that you plug in to your car, our smart phone app that you download, or other technology capable of recording the necessary data. We then analyze this information to provide you with personalized feedback and calculate a discount on your insurance premium in accordance with our Terms and Conditions. As part of the SmartRide Program we may collect information about your vehicle, such as driving speed, trip information and geolocation. If you download and use the mobile app, we may collect information about your mobile device as well. For additional information, please review the SmartRide Terms and Conditions of Use contained in the box your telematics device arrived in or contained in the End User License Agreement located under settings of the SmartRide app. 

## Information Sharing

### Information We Share for Servicing

Nationwide may share your personal information only as described in this Privacy Policy. We will not sell your information.

When you buy a product, we may share your information with other Nationwide companies or our business partners to service your product, to conduct research and analytics, to develop our website, and to conduct surveys. They may track and keep aggregated visitor information. We may also share your information with your agent, investment advisor, investment company, broker-dealer, or transfer agent affiliates. They use your information to manage your policy or account.

We also share and disclose your information for everyday business and servicing purposes and as permitted by law. You cannot opt out of these. Some examples include:

  * Mailing your statements or processing transactions that you request
  * As required by law, such as responding to a subpoena or governmental requests
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * Disclosing your information in connection with the sale or purchase of a business. If Nationwide is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information

### Information We Share for Marketing

We want our customers to have choices about how and when they do business with us. So Nationwide sells insurance, investment, and banking products through many different sales channels, such as agents, the Internet, or over the phone. All of these different sales channels make it easy for you to buy our products and interact with us. Some examples of our sales channels include:

  * Nationwide agents who sell Nationwide auto, home and life insurance
  * Independent insurance agents who sell products from many different insurance carriers
  * An independent broker-dealer who sells Nationwide annuities
  * Your bank, or another affinity group that you belong to, might offer Nationwide products
  * Your employer may offer a Nationwide retirement plan

Each sales channel has a specific privacy statement, which explains how we use your information, including how we share it for marketing purposes. To learn more, select your privacy statement from the list included in the box labeled "Privacy Statement for Your Specific Product."

### Choices to Limit Sharing

You can ask us not to share your information with other Nationwide companies or our business partners to market new products to you. Please remember, we offer many different types of products and services. You may not want to opt out if you would like to learn about these products directly from one of our companies. Please call us toll free at 1-866-280-1809 to opt out of this sharing. You may opt out at any time and we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. If you would like to discontinue receiving marketing emails from Nationwide, you may do so by using the "Unsubscribe" link found in emails we send to you.

### If you have already opted out, you don't need to opt out again.

If you don't want your registered representative to take your information to a new broker-dealer, please call us toll free at 1-877-233-3370.

## Access to Personal Information

You may ask us for a copy of your personal information so you may review it and correct or change it if necessary. Each of our companies has different contact information and instructions for requesting this information. We have included links to these products and companies in the box labeled "Privacy Statement for Your Specific Product." We will respond to your request within a reasonable time frame. To correct information, you may log in to your online account and make the updates, or you may call us or contact your agent to correct the information. If we received information from an institutional source, such as a consumer reporting agency, you will have to contact them directly. You'll want to review the specific privacy policy for the product you own for these instructions.

## Confidentiality and Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. We use reasonable physical and technical safeguards to protect your personal information, both during transmission and once we receive it. When you enter sensitive information (such as a Social Security number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL.) No method of transmission over the Internet, including via email, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure so, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. You may contact us at [nomail@nationwide.com](mailto:nomail@nationwide.com) if you have any questions or concerns regarding the confidentiality and security of your information.

We limit access to your personal information to those who need it to do their jobs. The law requires our business partners to use your personal information only for our purposes. They may not share it or use it in any other way. We comply with all federal and state data security laws.

## Dispute Resolution

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

## Changes to Privacy Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes in our information practices. If we make material changes to our privacy policy, we’ll post the changes right here and notify you by posting a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Confidentiality for Victims of Domestic Violence

New York State Insurance Law 2612 prohibits insurers from discriminating against victims of domestic violence. This law requires insurance companies to comply with valid orders of protection against an insured or anyone covered under an insured’s policy. While the order is in place, the insurance company is prohibited from sharing the address and telephone number of the protected persons, or of any person or entity providing covered services to the protected person. If a child is the protected person, the child’s parent or guardian must assert these rights.

### Nationwide's Obligation

Except in instances where express consent of the requestor is given, Nationwide will not disclose to the policyholder or another insured covered under the policy the: address, telephone number or any other personally identifying information of the covered individual or children residing with the covered individual. Nationwide is also prohibited from disclosing any information relating to abuse including the nature of the health care services provided to the covered individual. This information could include the: name, address, and telephone number of the provider of the health care services; or any other information that could lead to the discovery of the above information.

Where applicable, you have the ability to further protect yourself by creating a new online account with new credentials and by placing your policy in your own name.

### Requests for coverage

Please feel free to submit a valid order of protection to the below listed address:

**Nationwide Mutual Insurance Company  
Attn: Nationwide Service of Process   
1 Nationwide Blvd., 1-30-403   
Columbus, OH 43215   
Toll Free Line: 1-877-764-0418**

If the covered individual is a child, the parent or guardian may make the above request. To revoke a request or request to receive information at an alternative address, please contact our customer service.

**For more information, contact:**   
NYS Domestic and Sexual Violence Hotline: 800-942-6906   
In NYC: 1-800-621-HOPE (4673) TTY: 1-866-604-5350

## Contact Us

Nationwide World Headquarters One Nationwide Plaza   
Columbus, OH 43215-2220   
1-800-882-2822

## Nationwide Companies

Nationwide is one of the largest insurance and financial services companies in the world, focusing on domestic property and casualty insurance, life insurance, retirement savings, asset management and strategic investments. For a list of Nationwide subsidiaries and affiliates, please visit nationwide.com/affiliated-companies.jsp or call us at 1-877-ON YOUR SIDE® (1-877-669-6877).

This privacy policy was updated on **June 2, 2017**
